Sam Lehman

System Administrator

Reading, Pennsylvania US

☑ hire@samlehman.dev ☐ +1 (814) 528-3891

git Lehmanator (https://codeberg.org/Lehmanator)

• Lehmanator (https://github.com/Lehmanator)

Lehmanator (https://fosstodon.org/@Lehmanator)



Sam is a system administrator that deploys & manages workstations & infrastructure running a wide array of operating systems and software services. Sam has a depth & breadth of experience using programming languages, shell scripting, & declarative code for managing, running, and deploying servers & workstations.

SKILLS

Operating Systems

Windows | MacOS | Linux | Android | iOS | NixOS | Arch Linux | Debian

Nix

Nix | NixOS | reproducible builds | functional programming | immutability

Microsoft Azure

Directory servers | Domain controllers | Cloud computing | Cloud VMs | Office 365 | OAuth2

Scripting

PowerShell | Bash | Zsh | Nushell | Python

Kubernetes

Helm | Ceph | Flannel | NGINX-Ingress | Cert-Manager | Prometheus

Web Development

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Typescript | Node.js | React.js | Webpack.js | Babel.js | Django | Python | NGINX

Deployment

Ansible | Virtual Machines | Terraform | GitHub Actions | GitHub Pages | Forgejo Actions

Containers

Podman | Docker | Docker Compose | OCI | Container registries

Remote Management

SSH | RDP | VNC | journald | Group Policy Objects | Wireguard tunnels | Tailscale

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aug 2021 - Nov 2023

System Administrator at Presque Isle Wine Cellars

Responsible for administration of servers and all user workstations for the entire company.

- Migrated local domain controller to Azure cloud.
- Migrated local servers to container-based infrastructure.
- Migrated local databases to cloud-based PostgreSQL instance.
- Managed virtual machines running company infrastructure.
- Managed DNS server & configured records to improve security, routing behavior, and standards compliance
- Deployed internal company mesh VPN to secure company infrastructure in remote & hybrid work environments.
- Enhanced mail server security by configuring DMARC, DKIM, & SPF DNS records.
- Created Group Policy Objects (GPOs) to push configuration updates to remote Windows workstations.

Feb 2020 - May 2020

Software Engineering Intern at Brazen

Developed features for video conferencing platform & chatbots for automated candidate onboarding.

- Wrote Java code with Tensorflow API to integrate chatbot NLP agents with custom business logic.
- Wrote frontend & backend code in Java for video conferencing web platform.

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

GE Transportation (now Wabtec) is a global leader in locomotive manufacturing.

- Wrote C program to validate configurations to control locomotive hardware.
- Wrote Python program to analyze locomotive schematics for possible points of failure.
- Wrote Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) code to integrate Python & C programs with Excel spreadsheets used by engineers.

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

Electrical Integration - Software Engineering Intern at General Electric: Transportation

GE Transportation (now Wabtec) is a global leader in locomotive manufacturing.

- Wrote C program to validate configurations to control locomotive hardware.
- Wrote Python program to analyze locomotive schematics for possible points of failure.
- Wrote Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) code to integrate Python & C programs with Excel spreadsheets used by engineers.

PROJECTS

nix-configs

Mar 2023 - Current

https://codeberg.org/Lehmanator/nix-configs

Skills acquired: Kubernetes | Helm | Nix | NixOS | DevOps | CI / CD | deployment | infrastructure-as-code

- Declarative configurations representing both personal workstations and server infrastructure.
- Encrypted secret management with sops.
- Deployment of configurations via SSH.
- Running many self-hosted server applications in Kubernetes

resume.nix

Jan 2024 - Current

https://resume.samlehman.dev

Skills acquired: Nix | GitHub | GitHub Pages | GitHub Actions | DevOps | Node.js | static site | reproducible builds | declarative | CI / CD

- Reproducible environment that pulls locked dependencies to build artifacts for my resume.
- Builds an static webpage and PDF of my resume.
- Automatically deploys successfully built artifacts to GitHub Pages using GitHub Actions.
- Development shell with automatic installations of dependencies needed to hack on, build, and deploy my resume.

HeylmHungry

Mar 2019 - May 2020

https://github.com/Lehmanator/HeyImHungry

Skills acquired: Javascript | Node.js | React.js | Google Assistant | Google Cloud | Firebase

- React & React Native frontend.
- Google Assistant interface to query & add listings.

VOLUNTEER _

Sep 2018 - Apr 2019

Technology Captain at THON

THON is a student-run non-profit organization raising money for pediatric cancer research and the children affected by it. The THON Technology committee develops software to facilitate volunteer work and manage the annual dance marathon event.

- Containerized developer environment to speed up onboarding new volunteer developers.
- Containerized production webserver to make production environment reproducible.
- Used Python & Django to create informational webpages to update volunteers on latest events & news.
- Used Python & Django to create forms to collect and process information from volunteers.

EDUCATION

2014 - Current

Computer Science at Penn State University

LANGUAGES

English Native speaker

Spanish Intermediate

INTERESTS

Home Automation

Skills acquired: Home Assistant | ESPHome | Self-Hosting | Raspberry Pi | Helm charts | Docker | PostgreSQL | ESP32 | Microcontrollers | Circuitry | Automation

Self-Hosting

Skills acquired: Kubernetes | OpenID Connect | OAuth | Networking | DNS | IPv4 | IPv6

Fitness & Sports

Skills acquired: Weight lifting | Wrestling | Martial arts | Health

REFERENCES

"It's my pleasure to recommend Sam. He single-handedly moved our business IT into the 21st century. Any company would be lucky to have him. "

Lauri Lewis